Maryland Citizens Against State Executions; Records apap340
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Maryland Citizens Against State Executions Records
1962-2013
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap340
4.9 cubic ft.
The Maryland Citizens Against State Executions (Maryland or MD CASE) Records contain documents from over 25 groups and 1,300 individuals that united to help successfully end the death penalty in Maryland in 2013 through education, grassroots action, and public demonstration. The collection consists of correspondence, meeting minutes, legislation, lobbying materials, subject files, special event and conference materials, case files and clippings.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Jane Henderson, executive director, of Maryland Citizens Against State Executions donated all of the materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2013.
Administrative History
Maryland Citizens Against State Executions (Maryland or MD CASE) is a coalition of over 25 groups and 1,300 individuals that united to help successfully end the death penalty in Maryland in 2013 through education, grassroots action, and public demonstration. Founded in 1997 and formally incorporated in 2000 as the Maryland Coalition Against State Executions, the group changed its name in 2003.
The decade leading to the abolishment of the death penalty in Maryland in 2013 witnessed significant activity in the debate over capital punishment in the state. In 2002 Maryland Governor Parris Glendening declared a moratorium on executions, which his successor Robert Ehrlich ended in 2004. The last state sanctioned execution occurred in 2005. In 2008, the Maryland Commission on Capital Punishment was created to study all aspects of capital punishment in the state and make recommendations regarding future use. Following completion of its study, the Commission recommended the death penalty be abolished in the state. After earlier attempts to enact similar legislation failed, both houses of the Maryland Legislature voted in favor of a bill to repeal the death penalty for future offenders in March 2013 which Governor Martin O'Malley then signed into law. As of May 2014, four men remain on Death Row in Maryland, all convicted and sentenced before 2013.
Maryland CASE was highly engaged in the debate during the years between 2003 and 2013, as evidenced by the plethora of event fliers, brochures and postcards in the collection. Today Maryland CASE remains active and is overseen by an involved board of death penalty activists. One of the alternatives to capital punishment Maryland CASE endorses is life without parole, which the organization asserts is acceptable to a majority of Maryland citizens.
Scope and Contents
The collection documents Maryland Citizens Against State Executions' ongoing efforts to repeal capital punishment in the state. It consists of correspondence, meeting minutes, legislation, lobbying materials, subject files, special event and conference materials, case files and clippings. Much of the collection is dedicated to files on inmates, the events held to demand their release and subsequent memorial/remembrance events held after executions.
When available, the archivist retained the original file names created by Maryland CASE.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Political Outreach and Lobbying, 1962-2013, Undated
Series 2 - General/Public Outreach, 1994-2013, Undated
Series 3 - Subject Files, 1998-2013, Undated
All series are arranged chronologically.
Death Penalty; Lethal injection (Execution)--Maryland; Capital Punishment--Maryland; Legislative Hearings--Maryland; Minutes; Newsletters; Correspondence; Memorandums; Fliers (printed matter); Postcards; Brochures; Testimonies; Maryland Citizens Against State Executions; Steele, Michael S.; O'Malley, Martin
- Political Outreach and Lobbying, 1962-2013; Undated; 1; 2.0 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records created by or about commissions, hearing notes, legislation, bills, testimonies, letters and other political outreach materials, collected or created by Maryland Citizens Against State Executions, intended to end the death penalty in Maryland.
  - Committee on Cap. Pun. - Report to the Legislative Council of MD, 1962 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to/from Politicians (includes press releases and media advisories), 1978; 2001-2003; 2005; 2009; 2012 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 2)
  - Court Proceedings, Testimony and Other Related Materials, 1978; 2002-2003; 2007-2009; 2011; Undated (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 3)
  - Tyrone Delano Gilliam v. State of Maryland, 1989; 1992; 1994; 1998-1999 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 4-5)
  - Appeals Materials, 1993; 1996; 2000; 2002-2005; 2008 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 6-7)
  - The Report of the Governor's Task Force on the Fair Imposition of Capital Punishment, 1996 December (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 8)
  - Mora Bill, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 9)
  - PG County Resolutions, 2000 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 10)
  - Moratorium Leg. B, 2000-2001 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 11)
  - Commissions and Commission Information, 2001; 2006-2009; Undated (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 12)
  - Research: Scholarly Articles, Statistics, Polls, Talking Points and Other Materials, 2001/2013; Undated (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 13)
  - MD: General Assembly Materials, 2001; 2008-2009; 2011; 2013; Undated (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 14)
  - Petitions, 2002 May 07 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 15)
  - Congressional Achievement Award to Salima Siler Marriott, 2002 November 06 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 16)
  - Bryant, Cof. Appeals, 2002 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 17)
  - Leg. Session, 2002 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 18)
  - Oken Court Appeals, 2002 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 19)
  - Opposition, 2002-2003 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 20)
  - MD Leg. Session, 2002-2004; Undated (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 21)
  - Legislator Letter to Steele, 2003 June (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 22)
  - Leg. Black Caucus, 2003 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 23)
  - MD Leg. Session, 2003 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 24)
  - Schiebeir Testimony, 2003 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 25)
  - MD SB 744 - Comm. on Capital Punishment, 2004 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 26)
  - NAACP - MD Race Amicus, 2004 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 27)
  - Oken - Lethal Injection Appeal, 2004 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 28)
  - Repeal Bill, 2004 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 29)
  - Legislative Session, 2004-2005; Undated (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 30)
  - Leg. Session, 2004; 2008; Undated (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 31)
  - Evans v. Maryland - Record Extract - Vol. 1, 2005 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 32-33)
  - Evans v. Maryland - Record Extract - Vol. 2, 2005 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 34-36)
  - MD PAC Info., 2005 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 37)
  - Repeal, 2005 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 38)
  - Commission Bill, 2005-2006 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 39)
  - Evans v. Maryland - Brief for Appellants, 2005-2006 (Box 1 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 40)
  - Proposal MD Regulations, 2005-2006; 2008-2010 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 1)
  - Leg. Repeal Hearings, 2006 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 2)
  - Lethal Injection (APA Civil), 2006; Undated (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 3)
  - Resolutions, 2006-2007 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 4)
  - Legislation Session, 2006-2007; Undated (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 5)
  - O'Malley Email Action, 2007 March 20 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 6)
  - Black Caucus, Senates Letters to Governor, 2007 November (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 7)
  - Media Advisory Packet, 2007 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 8)
  - Miles Decision, 2007 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 9)
  - Session MGA Letters, 2007 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 10)
  - Venable Memos, 2007 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 11)
  - Commission Bill, 2008 April 07 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 12)
  - MD Commission on Capital Punishment, 2008 July 28 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 13)
  - Commission on Capital Punishment, 2008 August 05 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 14)
  - Commission, 2008 August 19 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 15)
  - Commission, 2008 September 05 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 16)
  - Commission Hearing Testimony, 2008 September 22 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 17)
  - Commission, 2008 October 07 (Box 2 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 18)
  - Court Information and Rules, 2008 July 08; Undated (Box 3 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 1)
  - Commission on Capital Punishment Commissioner Bios, 2008; Undated (Box 3 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 2)
  - Commission Info, 2008; Undated (Box 3 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 3)
  - MD CASE, Senate Bills, 2008-2009; Undated (Box 3 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 4)
  - Memorandum, 2009 June 04; Undated (Box 3 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 5)
  - Repeal to Reform Bill, 2009 (Box 3 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 6)
  - Fingerprint Evidence, 2009-2010 (Box 3 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 7)
  - Legislative Materials, 2009; 2013 (Box 3 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 8)
  - MD CASE: Administrative Files, 2010 (Box 3 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 9)
  - Data and Research: Figures and Tables, Undated (Box 3 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 10)
  - Hearing Notes, Undated (Box 3 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 11)
  - Hunt, Flint Gregory: Memorandum and Order, Undated (Box 4 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 1)
  - Illinois Commission Analysis on Maryland, Undated (Box 4 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 2)
  - Legislative/Organizing, Undated (Box 4 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 3)
  - MD: Capital Punishment Studies, Undated (Box 4 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 4)
  - Repeal Campaign Strategy (Strategic Map), Undated (Box 4 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 5)
  - Steele, Undated (Box 4 (1-Political Outreach and Lobbying), Folder 6)
- General/Public Outreach, 1994-2013; Undated; 2; 1.5 cubic ft.
  This series contains public opinion polls, event advertisements, information on related organizations (including student organizations), letters to legislators from citizens, fact sheets and other research.
  - MD CASE: Archives, 1994; 2000-2004 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 1)
  - One More Voice, 1998 (Video-tape 1)
  - Baldus' Preliminary Race Analysis, 2001 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 2)
  - MD: Sun Ad, Prominent Signer, 2001 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 3)
  - MD Death Row Cases, 2001-2002; 2004; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 4)
  - General Outreach: Misc. Materials, 2001-2003; 2008-2010; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 5)
  - DOJ Report on Race and Death Penalty, 2002 December 13 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 6)
  - MD Cath. Conf., 2002 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 7)
  - MD Moratorium, 2002 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 8)
  - MD Student Organizing, 2002-2003 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 9)
  - PG County Organizing Contacts, 2002-2004 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 10)
  - MD Strategy Planning, 2002-2004; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 11)
  - Race and the Death Penalty, 2002; 2004 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 12)
  - Fiscal Sponsorship, 2002; 2005-2006 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 13)
  - MD Justice Policy Institute Study, 2003 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 14)
  - MD COE Seminar, 2003-2004 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 15)
  - Mailings and Postcards, 2003; 2006-2009; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 16)
  - Empirical Analysis of the Imposition of the Death Penalty in Maryland, 2004 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 17)
  - MD Students Against the Death Penalty, 2004 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 18)
  - Mount St. Mary's College, 2004; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 19)
  - MD Crime Reports, 2004-2005 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 20)
  - MD Editorial Packet, 2004-2005 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 21)
  - Baker Execution - Mailing, 2005 November 22 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 22)
  - Begging, 2005 April (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 23)
  - Postcard - Race/Oral Argument, 2005 June (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 24)
  - Bonnita, 2005 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 25)
  - Duncan, 2005 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 26)
  - Helen Prejean Visit, 2005 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 27)
  - Mailing Appeal, 2005 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 28)
  - Polling-MD, 2005 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 29)
  - Hell Week Originals, 2005; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 30)
  - MD CASE Packet, 2005; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 31)
  - Afro American Ad, 2005-2006 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 32)
  - OMW Opera, 2005-2006 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 33)
  - Press Releases and Newspapers, 2005-2006 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 34)
  - Mont. Co. Citizens of Faith, 2005-2006; 2008 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 35)
  - Brochures and Magazines, 2005-2006; 2009; 2011-2012 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 36-37)
  - Ask Ehrlich and Steele, 2006 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 38)
  - Death Penalty Information Center, 2006 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 39)
  - From the Death House to the Courthouse, 2006 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 40)
  - Member Organization (CASE), 2006 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 41)
  - Press Releases, 2006 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 42)
  - Witness and Action, 2006 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 43)
  - Witness and Action: Christian Responses to the Death Penalty, 2006 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 44)
  - Board of Directors Information, Charts, Notes and Other Materials, 2006; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 45)
  - Annapolis U.U. Church, 2006-2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 46)
  - Archived Newsletters, 2006-2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 47)
  - "In Her Honor" Memorial Information, 2006-2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 48)
  - LTE's, 2006-2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 49)
  - Maryland Commission on Capital Punishment: Findings and Recommendation, 2006; 2011; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 50)
  - Newsletters, 2006-2012 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 51)
  - Maryland Catholic Conference, 2007 April 04 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 52)
  - Active Voice/RTE Screening, 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 53)
  - Ads, 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 54)
  - Beyond the Bottom Line, 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 55)
  - Frederick-In the Streets, 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 56)
  - Institute for Race and Justice Materials, 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 57)
  - Legislative Packets, 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 58)
  - MGA Religious Sign On, 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 59)
  - Mailing Archives, 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 60)
  - Post: "A Governor Stands Up", 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 61)
  - Reggie Lewis Event, 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 62)
  - Strategy Stuff, 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 63)
  - Sun: "End the Death Penalty", 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 64)
  - Takoma Park Street Fest., 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 65)
  - University of Baltimore Law Forum, 2007 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 66)
  - Amnesty Int., 2007; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 67)
  - MD Polling, 2007; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 68)
  - Polling (District), 2007; 2009 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 69)
  - At the Death House Door, 2008 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 70)
  - EJUSA Files, 2008 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 71)
  - MD Fundraising Files, 2008 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 72)
  - Progressive Summit, 2008 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 73)
  - Repeal Nights-Camden Yards, 2008 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 74)
  - State Death Penalty Abolition Coordinator: Resource Manual, 2008 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 75)
  - Urban Institute Study & 2008 Report on the MD Committee on Capital Punishment (Cd 1)
  - Hood College Community Service Fair, 2008/2009 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 76)
  - "The Cost of the Death Penalty" and Other Materials, 2008; 2011; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 77)
  - Resolutions, Articles and Other Materials, 2008-2013 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 78)
  - "Voices of Change: Death Penalty Repeal" Poster, 2009 February 12 (Flat-file 1)
  - Death Penalty, 2009 February 24 (Cd 2)
  - "At the Death House Door": Snack Voucher, 2009 March (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 79)
  - Communications, 2009-2010 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 80)
  - Fact Sheet Originals, 2009; 2011; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 81)
  - Events, 2009; 2011-2012; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 82)
  - Polls, 2010 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 83)
  - Campaign, 2011 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 84)
  - LI-Berkley "Comments" (water damaged), 2011 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 85)
  - NCADP, 2011 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 86)
  - MD Fact Sheets and Other Materials, 2011; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 87)
  - Fliers & Informative Posters, 2011-2013; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 88)
  - Pamphlets, Fliers & Other Materials, 2011-2013; Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 89)
  - State Voices, 2012 (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 90)
  - Ad Rate Cards, Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 91)
  - An Empirical Analysis of MD's Death Sentencing System, Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 92)
  - Brochures, Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 93)
  - The Case for Repeal, Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 94)
  - Cath. Con. Poll, Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 95)
  - Executions Create More Victims, Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 96)
  - Fair and Equal Under the Law?, Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 97)
  - Faith-Based Res, Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 98)
  - Fliers, Undated (Box 1 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 99)
  - FPC Lifenet Legal Defense Campaign Event - Play I, Undated (Cd 3)
  - Home Partner, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 1)
  - How to Get Your Res Passed, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 2)
  - Impact on Victims, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 3)
  - "Innocent Lives in the Balance", Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 4)
  - Invitations to Fundraisers, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 5)
  - Law Enforcement Letter, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 6)
  - Lobby Night, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 7)
  - MD CASE/The Abell Foundation Packet, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 8)
  - MD Citizens Against State Executions packet, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 9)
  - Proposal MD Regulations, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 10)
  - Old Fact Sheets, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 11)
  - Old Letterhead, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 12)
  - Opera Postcard, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 13)
  - OSI - Bonnita Stuff, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 14)
  - Postcards/Fliers, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 15)
  - Postcards to Officials, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 16)
  - Resolution for Repeal, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 17)
  - Signed Letters Requesting End of DP, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 18)
  - Speech Notes, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 19)
  - Stopmax Conference FPC - Workshop Session, Undated (Cd 4)
  - Victims' Letters, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 20)
  - Wasteful and Expensive, Undated (Box 2 (2-General/Public Outreach), Folder 21)
- Subject Files, 1998-2013; Undated; 3; 1.4 cubic ft.
  This series contains a diverse collection of material from or associated with Maryland Citizens Against State Executions. The files contain research, articles, inmate files, legislator files, politician files, press materials, analysis, and reports.
  - MRJ, 1998 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Collins, Kenneth, 2000 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Borchart Court Appeals, 2000-2001; 2005-2006 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting, 2000-2001; 2003-2005; 2007; 2009 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - MD: CASE - General Clippings About the Death Penalty, 2000-2013; Undated (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Background on MD CASE, 2000; 2008; 2010 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - MD Media: Articles & OPed's, 2001-2002; 2005 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - MD CASE: Research & Correspondence, 2001-2003; 2006; 2008-2009; 2012 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Oken Sign-On Letter, 2001-2004; Undated (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Articles, 2001; 2005; 2013 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Newspaper: Gazette/Voters Guide, 2002 August 29 (Flat-file 2)
  - Baltimore Co., 2002 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Glen Ivey, 2002 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - MD - Post Moratorium Coverage, 2002 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Oken - Care Facts Summary, 2002 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Logan Care - PG Co., 2002-2003 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Opposition Research, 2002-2003 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - "Washington Sniper", 2002-2003 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Wiggins, 2002-2003 (Box 1 (3-Subject Files), Folder 18)